http://www.harborough-anglican.org.uk/data-privacy-notice

Data Privacy Notice1. Your personal data – what is it?Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) and the Data protection Act 2018.2. Who are we?The Harborough Anglican Team comprises of the Parochial Church Councils of St Dionysius, Market Harborough, All Saints, Lubenham, St Peter & St Paul, Great Bowden, and The Parish of the Transfiguration (St Nicholas and St Hugh) . The PCCs of the team churches are the Data controllers of their churches (contact details below). This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.3. How do we process your personal data?Members of The Harborough Anglican Team and its constituent Parochial Church Councils comply with its obligations under this data protection legislation by keeping personal data up to date; storing and destroying it securely; not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data. We use your personal data for the following purposes: -• To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution;• To administer the records of those who consider themselves part of the church;• To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity;• To manage all employees and volunteers;• To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);• To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at each church.• To share your contact details with The Harborough Anglican Staff and Ministry Teams so they can keep you informed about news and events, activities and services that will be occurring within the team in which you may be interested.4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?• Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about events within The Harborough Anglican Team of Churches.• Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;• Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a religious aim provided: the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and• there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.5. Sharing your personal dataYour personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the staff and ministry teams who work across churches which are part of the the Harborough Anglican Team in order to carry out a service to those who consider themselves to be part of the church or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your details with third parties outside of the Team with your consent.6. How long do we keep your personal data?We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church of England website:https://www.churchofengland.org/sites/default/files/2017-11/care_of_parish_records_keep_or_bin_-_2009_edition.pdfSpecifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently. In the case of safeguarding records for 50 years after an event has ended.7. Your rights and your personal dataUnless subject to an exemption under Data Protection Legislation, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: -• The right to request a copy of your personal data which The Harborough Anglican Team holds about you;• The right to request that The Harborough Anglican Team corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;• The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for The Harborough Anglican Team to retain such data;• The right to request the withdrawal of your consent to the processing at any time• The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable) [Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means].• The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;• The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable) [Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]• The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.8. Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Privacy Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.9. Contact DetailsTo exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints please in the first instance contact your Data Protection Administrators or the Team Office. You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.Contact details of all clergy, Church Officers within the Harborough Anglican Team can be found in the Team Magazine - The Quintet.10. Data Protection & Privacy PolicyFor sight of the Church of England Privacy and Cookie Policy please refer to:https://www.churchofengland.org/privacy-and-cookies
